Guide to the Group Material Archive 1976-2009 (bulk 1979-1996) MSS 215
Fales Library and Special Collections
Group Material Archive
Bulk, 1979-1996
1976-2009
MSS 215
Fales Library and Special Collections
57.0 boxes
Active from 1979-1996, Group Material was an artists' collaboration that produced over forty-five projects addressing a wide range of social, political, and artistic issues. Members included Doug Ashford, Julie Ault, Felix Gonzalez-Torres, Mundy McLaughlin, Karen Ramspacher and Tim Rollins, among others. The collective also worked with artists such as Vito Acconci, Mike Glier, Barbara Kruger, Mierle Laderman Ukeles, Faith Ringgold, Martha Rosler, Andres Serrano, Nancy Spero, Anton van Dalen, Carrie Mae Weems, and many others. Materials in the collection document the origins, processes and context of Group Material's activities.
Group Material (Firm: New York, N.Y.).
Conditions Governing Access
Open to researchers. Appointments are necessary for the use of manuscript and archival collections.
Arrangement
All efforts were made to preserve the original arrangement of the collection. Within each series, most items are arranged chronologically, when material is dated.
Materials that are not arranged chronologically are noted in the detailed series descriptions, found in the Container List.
Certain materials are also grouped by format (including Photographic Material, Video, Audio, Computer Discs, and Objects). The researcher should expect to find some overlapping of materials throughout all series.
Oversized archival materials from the various series are listed at the end of the finding aid.
The Group Material Archive is arranged in the following series:
[detailed series and subseries descriptions can be found in the container list]
Series I: Project Files
Series II: Correspondence
Series III: Press and Promotional Material
Series IV: Clippings
Series V: Financial files
Series VI: Photographic Material
Series VII: Video
Series VIII: Audio
Series IX: Computer files
Series X: Objects
Series XI: "Vital Archive" (Accretion 2011)
Oversize Series I: Project Files
Oversize Series II: Correspondence
Oversize Series III: Press and Promotional Material
Oversize Series VI: Photographic Material
Oversize Series X: Objects
Scope and Content
The Group Material archive is comprised of working notes, meeting minutes, proposals, posters, flyers, announcements, installation photographs, source material, press releases, magazine articles, reviews, financial documents, color slides, catalogs, audio tapes, video tapes, computer discs, artifacts, artworks, ephemera, and exhibition materials. Julie Ault assembled the archive in the summer and fall of 2008, with contributions from Doug Ashford, Sonia Finley, Sabrina Locks, and Rasmus Röhling.
The archive also includes artwork by Vito Acconci, Dennis Adams, Ida Applebroog, Doug Ashford, Julie Ault, Jimmy De Sana, Gran Fury, Mike Glier, Felix Gonzalez-Torres, Michael Jenkins, Barbara Kruger, Mundy McLaughlin, Aric Obrosey, Saul Ostrow, Richard Prince, Tim Rollins, Martha Rosler, Andres Serrano, Kiki Smith, Nancy Spero, Haim Steinbach, Carrie Mae Weems, among many others.
Provenance
Julie Ault assembled the Group Material Archive by compiling her own material, which included some that was previously integrated from Mundy McLaughlin and Tim Rollins, and combining it with material from Doug Ashford and from other group members. NYU Libararies acquired the Group Material Archive in 2008.
Ault outlines her archiving process in greater detail in the book Show and Tell: A Chronicle of Group Material:
"The group’s material traces had been dispersed since 1983 when the collaborative decided it would no longer maintain an exhibition space or headquarters and instead function nomadically, working from members’ homes and aided by the temporary infrastructural support of art institutions that invited GM to make projects. Decentralized, members kept their own paper trails or not. While no single person had the official responsibility of keeping up documentation of GM’s process and projects, former member Mundy McLaughlin did so for the most part until 1986, at which point I took over the informal role, as well as the files. Founding member Tim Rollins gave me his files soon after. Others who left did not turn their collected material over to those who continued. What remains tangible for the archive, thirty years after GM’s founding, is a mixture of several individuals’ saving habits stimulated by idiosyncratic, conceptual, and practical factors. Some of what was saved is of ambiguous value and much that should have been kept was not. Things got lost and thrown out early on because as barely solvent young New Yorkers we had space constraints and moved frequently."
Historical Note
"Group Material was founded by a number of artists who sought a collaborative practice in which they could fuse their interests in art and politics. The original thirteen members included Tim Rollins, Patrick Brennan, Julie Ault, Mundy McLaughlin, Marybeth Nelson, and Beth Jaker. In 1980 and 1981 Group Material operated a storefront exhibition space on East Thirteenth Street, where it staged a series of shows focused on social themes.
After 1981 the group shrunk to three members and chose not to maintain its own space but instead to create installations in existing venues (alternative art spaces, university galleries, and museums) and multiform projects in public (primarily through interventions using public advertising spaces). Doug Ashford joined the group in 1982, Felix Gonzalez-Torres in 1987, Karen Ramspacher in 1989, and Thomas Eggerer and Jochen Klein in 1995. Group Material's dense installations were typically thematic and combined fine art in various media and styles, mass-produced items, and artifacts to form designed environments. These exhibitions were concerned with topical issues or debates in culture and politics and were institution- or site-dependent, such as “Subculture” on the IRT subway trains in 1982; "Democracy" at the Dia Art Foundation in 1988; and "AIDS Timeline" at the University Art Museum, University of California at Berkeley, in 1989. Group Material ceased its activities in 1996."
Chronology:
1980 Group Material opens storefront at 244 E. 13th Street in the Lower East Side
October 4-27,1980 "Inaugural Exhibition", Group Material, 244 E. 13th Street, New York
November 4-11, 1980 "The Salon Election of '80", Group Material, 244 E. 13th Street, New York
November 22-December 21, 1980 "ALIENATION", Group Material, 244 E. 13th Street, New York
January 10-February 1, 1981 "The People's Choice (Arroz con Mango)", Group Material, 244 E. 13th Street, New York
February 14-March 9, 1981 “It’s a Gender Show!”, Group Material, 244 E. 13th Street, New York
March 7th, 1981 “Revolting Music”, The Machinist’s Union Hall, New York
March 21-April 20, 1981 "Consumption: Metaphor, Pastime, Necessity", Group Material, 244 E. 13th Street, New York
May 2-June 4, 1981 "Facere/Fascis", Group Material, 244 E. 13th Street, New York
June 14th-30th, 1981 "Atlanta: An Emergency Exhibition", Group Material, 244 E. 13th Street, New York
July 11, 1981 "Eat This Show", Group Material, 244 E. 13th Street, New York
August, 1981 Group Material awarded its first NEA grant
October 31-November 28th, 1981 "Enthusiasm!", Group Material Headquarters, 132 E. 26th street, New York
December 10, 1981-January 10, 1982 "M5", Interior bus advertisements, Fifth Avenue bus lines, New York
April 16, 1982 "DA ZI BAOS", 14th Street and Park Avenue South, Union Square, New York
March 25-May 1, 1982 "Works on Newspaper", Group Material Headquarters, 132 E. 26th Street, New York
May 29-July 17, 1982 "Primer (for Raymond Williams)", Artists Space, 105 Hudson Street, New York
June 19-July 9, 1982 "Luchar!: An Exhibition for the People of Central America", Taller Latinoamericano/The Latin American Workshop, Inc., New York
April 14, 1982 "Revolutionary Fine Arts", Taller Latinoamericano, New York
September 1-30, 1983 "Subculture", Interior advertisements, IRT subway trains, New York. Concurrent exhibition held at Taller Latinoamericano, New York
January 22-March 18, 1984 "Timeline: A Chronicle of U.S. Intervention in Central and Latin America", P.S.1, New York
January 11-February 8, 1985 "A.D.: Christian Influence in Contemporary Culture", Work, New York
March 21-June 9, 1985 "Americana", 1985 Whitney Biennial, lobby gallery, Whitney Museum of American Art, New York
April 27-May 25, 1985 "Democracy Wall", Chapter Arts Centre, Cardiff, Wales
1985-1986 "MASS", various locations: Hallwalls, Buffalo, New York; The New Museum of Contemporary Art, New York; Los Angeles Contemporary Exhibitions, Los Angeles; Artspace, Sydney Australia, and others
September 1-October 12, 1985 "Messages to Washington", Washington Project for the Arts, Washington, DC
November 7-December 19, 1985 "Alarm Clock", "The Other America", Royal Festival Hall, London
February 22-March 22, 1986 "Liberty & Justice", Alternative Museum, 17 White Street, New York
May 24-June 14, 1986 "Arts and Leisure", The Kitchen, 519 W. 19th Street, New York
February 6-28, 1987 "Resistance (Anti-Baudrillard)", White Columns, 325 Spring Street, New York
June 12-September 20, 1987 "The Castle", "documenta 8", Museum Fridericianum, Kassel, Germany
May 22, 1988 "Inserts", Advertising supplement to the Sunday New York Times
September, 1988-January, 1989 "Democracy", Dia Art Foundation, 77 Wooster Street, New York
October 1-November 14, 1987 "Constitution", The Temple Gallery, Temple University, Tyler School of Art, Philadelphia
September 15-October 8, 1988 "Democracy: Education", Dia Art Foundation, 77 Wooster Street, New York
October 15-November 12, 1988 "Democracy: Politics and Election", Dia Art Foundation, 77 Wooster Street, New York
November 19-December 10, 1988 "Democracy: Cultural Participation", Dia Art Foundation, 77 Wooster Street, New York
December 19, 1968-January 14, 1989 "Democracy: AIDS and Democracy: A Case Study", Dia Art Foundation, 77 Wooster Street, New York
December 16, 1988-February 13, 1989 "AIDS & Democracy" aka "Elegy", Vollbild AIDS, RealismusStudio, Neue Gesellschaft fur Bildende Kunst (NGBK), Berlin
June 1-December 1, 1989 "Unisex", The Center Show, The Lesbian and Gay Community Center, New York
October 14-November 26, 1989 "Shopping Bag", Shopping bags distributed in local shops and department stores, D&S Ausstellung, Kunstverein, Hamburg, Germany
November 11, 1989-January 28, 1990 "AIDS Timeline", Matrix Gallery, University Art Museum, University of California at Berkeley
February 23-March 30, 1990 "Your Message Here", Billboard project, Collaboration with Randolph Street Gallery, Chicago
June 26-July 5, 1990 "Democracy Poll", Insert in Der Togesspiegel, U-Bahn station, billboards, and an electronic billboard, RealismusStudio, Neue Gesellschaft fur Bildende Kunst (NGBK), Berlin
September 1-30, 1990 "AIDS & Insurance", Exterior bus advertisement, sponsored by Real Art Ways, Hartford, CT
September 30-November 18, 1990 "AIDS Timeline", Matrix Gallery, Wadsworth Athanaeum, Hartford, CT
October 26, 1990-January 13, 1991 "Collaboration" aka "Economics: Oberlin Project", "Social Studies: 4+4 Young Americans", The Allen Memorial Art Museum, Oberlin College, Oberlin, Ohio
April 19-June 23, 1991 "AIDS Timeline" (New York City 1991), 1991 Whitney Biennial, lobby gallery, The Whitney Museum of American Art, New York
December 17-20, 1991 "Cash Prize", Advertisements in the Seattle Post-Intelligencer, In Public: Seattle 1991, The Seattle Arts Commission, Seattle, Washington
October 8-December 31, 1993 "Tomorrow", Museum of Contemporary Art San Diego, La Jolla, CA
October 19, 1993-January 23, 1994 "Democracy Wall", In And Out Of Place, Museum of Fine Arts, Boston
May 6-June 18, 1995 "Market", Kunstverein München, Munich
June 7-23, 1996 "Program", Three Rivers Arts Festival, Pittsburgh, PA
Bibliography:
Bibliography
Ashford, D. (2006). A conversation on social collaboration. Art Journal, 65(2), 58-82. doi: 10.2307/20068466
Ault, J., Wallis, B., Weems, M., & Yenawine, P. (1999). Art matters: How the culture wars changed America. New York: New York University Press.
Ault, J. (2002). Alternative art, New York: 1965-1985. Minneapolis: University of Minnesota Press & New York: The Drawing Center.
Avgikos, J. (1995). Group Material Timeline: Activism as a work of art. In Nina Felshin, (Ed.), But is it art? (pp. 85-116). Seattle: Bay Press.
Fairbrother, T. J., Potts, K., & Museum of Fine Arts, Boston. (1993). In and out of place: contemporary Art and the American social landscape. Boston: Museum of Fine Arts.
Group Material (Firm: New York, N.Y.), & Temple Gallery (Philadelphia, Pa.). (1987). Constitution. Philadelphia, PA: Temple Gallery.
Group Material (Firm: New York, N.Y.), & Ault, J. (ed.) (2010). Show and tell: A chronicle of Group Material. London: Four Corners Books.
Lippard, L. R. (1984). Get the message?: A decade of art for social change. New York: E.P. Dutton.
Olander, W. (1989, January). Material world. Art in America, 167, 123–128.
Wallis, B., Group Material (Firm: New York, N.Y.), & Dia Art Foundation. (1990). Democracy: A project. Seattle: Bay Press & New York: Dia Art Foundation.
Related Archival Materials note
Related Material
The A.I.R. Gallery Archives, ca. 1972-2006
The Creative Time Archives, 1973-2006
Jimmy De Sana Papers 1954-1997 (bulk 1977-1990)
The Fashion Moda Archive 1978-1993
The Franklin Furnace Ephemera Collection, Compiled by Matthew Hogan, ca. 1970 - 2007 (Bulk 1985 - 2007)
Godzilla Asian American Arts Network Archive
The Guerrilla Girls Archive (unprocessed)
REPOhistory Archive 1911-1999 (Bulk 1989-1999)
The Paper Tiger Archive (unprocessed)
The Public Art Fund Archive, 1966-2009
The David Wojnarowicz Papers ca. 1954-1992
The Martin Wong Papers ca. 1982-1999
Separated Materials
Many books that were part of the archive have been removed, and will be cataloged as part of the Fales Downtown Book Collection.
A.I.R. Gallery (New York, N.Y.).; ABC No Rio (New York, N.Y.).; Acconci, Vito, 1940-; ACT UP (Organization).; Adams, Dennis; Ahearn, John, 1951-; Alderfer, Hannah; Annina Nosei Gallery.; Artforum.; Artists Space (Gallery) .; Ashford, Doug; Atkinson, Conrad; Ault, Julie; Beuys, Joseph; Brennan, Patrick; Dalen, Anton van; De Sana, Jimmy; Fashion Moda (Group).; Gay Men's Health Crisis, Inc.. AIDS Professional Education Program.; Gay Men's Health Crisis, Inc..; Gonzalez-Torres, Felix; Group Material (Firm: New York, N.Y.).; Group Material (Firm: New York, N.Y.).; Guerrilla Girls (Group of artists).; Hawkins, Yolanda; Howland, Rebecca; Kosuth, Joseph; Kruger, Barbara; McCarty, Marlene, 1957-; McLaughlin, Mundy; Nelson, Marybeth; New Museum of Contemporary Art (New York, N.Y.) .; New York (N.Y.). Dept. of Health and Mental Hygiene.; New York State Council on the Arts.; Ostrow, Saul; People with AIDS Coalition .; Planned Parenthood Federation of America.; Rollins, Tim, 1955-; Ronald Reagan; Rosler, Martha; School of Visual Arts (New York, N.Y.).; Serrano, Andres; Smith, Kiki, 1954-; Spero, Nancy, 1926-; Szypula, Peter; Taylor, Elizabeth; Tom of Finland; Tseng, Kwong Chi; Whitney Museum of American Art.; Wilde, Oscar, 1854-1900; Wojnarowicz, David; Wong, Martin; AIDS activists; Alternative spaces (Arts facilities); Alternative spaces (Arts facilities) |z New York (State) |z New York.; Art and society |z United States |x History |y 20th century.; Art and society.; Art patronage.; Art |v Exhibitions.; Art |x Exhibitions |z New York (State) |z New York.; Art |x Experimental methods.; Art |x Philosophy.; Art |x Political aspects.; Art, American |y 20th century.; Art, Modern |y 20th century |v Exhibitions.; Artists and community |z United States.; Artists |z New York (State) |z New York |v Exhibitions.; Artists |z New York (State) |z New York |x Political activity.; Artists |z United States.; Artists' writings.; Communication in art; Culture conflict |z United States.; Downtown Collection.; Drafts (documents).; DVDs.; East Village (New York, N.Y.); Ephemera.; Essays.; Exhibition catalogs.; Feminism and art.; Feminism.; Gender identity |z United States.; Group Material (Firm: New York, N.Y.); Group Material (Firm: New York, N.Y.) |x Constitution.; Group work in art.; Heresies Collective, inc.; Lower East Side (New York, N.Y.); National Endowment for the Arts.; SoHo (New York, N.Y.); SoHo (New York, N.Y.) |x Intellectual life.; Women |x Health and hygiene.
- Series I: Project Files
  Scope and Content
  Arranged chronologically, and by format, this series documents Group Material project history and activities. Materials include administrative documents, project notes, announcements, meetings of minutes, plans, drawings, publications and photographs. Series I is broken down into four subseries.
  - Subseries A: Projects at Group Material, 244 East 13th Street, 1976-1981
    This series documents Group Materials early formations and the activities surrounding Group Material's exhibition space at 244 East 13th Street.
    - Tim Rollins (Student work sent to Julie Ault), 1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Pre-Group Material, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Internal Statements and Communiqués, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Minutes of Meetings, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - "No More Witch Hunts", [1980] (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Early Group Material, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Proposal for a First Show, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Group Material "Inaugural Exhibition", 1980 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Statement of Purpose drafts and early notes, [1980] (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Group Material E. 13th St. Stationary, [1980] (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - "The Salon of Election" 1980, November 1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - "Alienation", November-December 1980 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 13th Street Art Workshops for Kids, December 1980 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Budgets and Finances, 1980-1983 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - "It's a Gender Show", 1981 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Gender Show, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Who/What/Where/When/Why Calendar, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - "The People's Choice (Arroz Con Mango)", January 1981 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - "Revolting Music", March 7, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - "Consumption: Metaphor, Pastime, Necessity", March-April 1981 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - "Facere/Fascis", May 1981 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - E. 13th St. Mailing List/Sign in Book, May 2nd-July 11, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - "An Emergency Exhibition: Atlanta", June 1981 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - "Eat This Show", July 11, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 25A)
    - GM Original Statements and Showgraphies, undated (Box 1, Folder 25B)
  - Subseries B: Projects exhibited in public spaces and other venues, 1981-1990
    In September of 1981, Group Material declared its intention to "develop a new practice based around distribution and employing public spaces." This series documents activities that occurred after Group Material abandoned the East 13th Street gallery and began to bring projects to other venues and public sites.
    - "Caution! Alternative Space", 1981 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - "Enthusiasm", October-November, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - "M5", December 1981-January 1982 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Group Material 2nd Year Calendar, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - General Correspondence, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Various Group Material Descriptions, 1982-1987 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - "Works on Newspaper", March-April 1982 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - "Vice and Virtue", Kenkeleba House, March-May 1982 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - "DA ZI BAOS", April 1982 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - "Primer (For Raymond Williams)", May-July 1982 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - "Luchar!: An Exhibition for the People of Central America", June-July 1982 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - "Revolutionary Fine Arts", April 14, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - John Malpede and Vanalyn Green Performance Event, May 1983 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - "Subculture", September 1983 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - "Subculture" - Subway panels 1-49, 1983 (Box 41)
    - "Subculture" - Subway panels 50-100, 1983 (Box 42)
    - Pity Puppy Fundraiser, November 1983 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - "Timeline: The Chronicle of U.S. Intervention in Central and Latin America", 1984 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - "A.D. Christian Influence in Contemporary Culture", January-February 1984 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - "Americana", 1985 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - "Democracy Wall" for Cardiff, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - "Messages to Washington", September-October 1985 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - "Alarm Clock" in the "Other America", September-October 1985 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - "MASS" Announcements, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - "MASS" 1 of 2, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - "MASS" 2 of 2, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - "Liberty and Justice", February-March 1986 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - "Arts and Leisure", May-June 1986 (Box 1, Folder 51)
      General note
      Contains two copies of "Arts and Leisure" catalog.
    - "Resistance (Anti-Baudrillard)", February 1987 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - "The Castle" (Show, Cat, Correspondence), June-September 1987 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - "The Castle" (Loans, Shipping, Finance), June-September 1987 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - "The Castle" (Announcements, PR, Promo), June-September 1987 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - "DA ZI BAOS" for Damon Brandt Show, September-October 1987 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - "Constitution", October-November 1987 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - "Inserts" - (Proposals, Correspondence, Administration), May 1988 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - "Inserts" - (Layouts, Ingredients, Results), May 1988 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - "Democracy" (Dia narratives and grant application), 1988 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "Democracy" (Press Releases, Announcement Forms), 1988 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - "Democracy" (Town Meetings), 1988 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - "Democracy" Checklists, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - "Democracy" (AIDS and Democracy Flyers and Research), 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - "Democracy" Guest Books and Comments, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - "Democracy" (Correspondence), 1988 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - "Democracy" (Miscellaneous Re: Exhibitions), 1988 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Roundtable and Town Meeting Transcriptions, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - "AIDS and Democracy: A Case Study" - Meeting Transcription, [1988] (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - "Democracy" (Reprint research for book), 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - "Democracy" (Image research for book, not used in book), 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - "Democracy" (Images for book, used) - 1 of 2, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - "Democracy" (Images for book, used) - 2 of 2, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - "Democracy" (Brochures and Ads for Book), 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - "Democracy" (Notes, Drafts, Statements for Book), 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Other Drafts for Book 1, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Other Drafts for Book 2, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Other Drafts for Book 3, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Other Drafts for Book 4, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Other Drafts for Book 5, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - "Vollbild AIDS", December 1988-February 1990 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence with Artists, [1989] (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Letters to the Editor - "AIDS and Democracy: A Case Study", 1989 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - "Democracy" (Essays - Rainer, Wallace, and Gates), 1989 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - "Unisex" for "The Center Show", March 1989 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - "Shopping Bag", October-November 1989 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - "Shopping Bag" - Shopping Bags, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Corcoran Non-Project, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - "AIDS Timeline" - Berkeley - A+Text-Versions/Notes, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - "AIDS Timeline" - Berkeley (Correspondence, checklists, show, process), 1989 (Box 3, Folder 3)